our locals will have the first go at it.
Um, you guys start.
>> Coach, can you take us through uh what
game model brings to you this season?
>> Um, yeah. I look obviously we're
excited. um
I would say this process took a while
and
credit um Miami and George the patience
of coming to a a real fair deal and and
but with with regards to the player he's
explosive. I think if you ask me the
single biggest thing that I think he
does well is he's extremely fast and he
stops fast. um he can sink his hips in
transition. Um and then the other thing
that came came up time and time again
was how competitive he is. I'm very
close with Teddy Bridgewwater. We're
very close with coach Sabin. We're close
with a lot of people who've um who've
had a chance to work with him. And uh
I think whenever you get into a bigname
free agent or a trade of this magnitude,
the all the other stuff is important to
research.
And so when it comes to waddles, all the
other stuff, it was 10 10 10 in. Um so I
think obviously it'll help us. He played
he played major
>> until the waddle trailer. There was a
lot of angst about
>> I know I know I know we tune out the
angst and there was a lot of angst when
we selected Bo where we selected them.
There was a lot of angst when we made
quite quite a few of these decisions and
look
>> well I'm going to finish.
>> You have to tune that out.
>> Now I said this in in a in a jokingly
manner. Um we're aware of that. like we
understand that and and yet you cannot
chase what others outside the building
feel like you should be doing. We spent
a lot of time on this free agency class.
Um we had a pecking order of what we
thought was most important and we were
able to accomplish that. Um,
now I'm sure as hell glad that we had
the waddle trade done before I was
coaching that damn flag football game
and and our fan base wasn't going crazy
as I'm working on a flag game plan. Um,
but I think in fairness and I recognize
everyone would say, "Hey, you got Bo on
his rookie deal." Well, no kidding.
Um, but
just do the do the research and and you
go back in that first week of free
agency and if you're batting 380 395,
that's about where the numbers lie. If
you went back five years from now, you
just just go backwards and said would
say, would they do it again?
Now, we we did a really good job in year
one of hitting on
some priority free agents that that
immediately were able to change
the flight pattern in which we were
traveling.
But I think
George and I felt strongly there were a
few of these players that really
a we were ressigning
that were already on our existing team
and b a number of these players who we
redid contracts with. Um, and so
that time of this season
has been marketed right in front of
every one of your eyes. What's the next
word that comes after free agency from
the NFL network, from NFL.com? What is
it? Frenzy. So, we want any it's
nothing.
Frenzy is is is what you don't want. And
frenzy implies it has to happen. Chaos.
Ah, and
it's all marketing. So, steady, right
decision. What's our plan? Stick with
our plan. Tune out the noise. Um, same
same's going to apply to this draft. We
don't know who's driving this bus, the
first round bus, I call it.
>> And if you're not careful, you'll end up
selecting a player that
maybe someone else thinks. So, um, we're
excited
to add a player like Jaylen. We spent we
spent a lot of time looking at that
selection
and trying to determine
we could
safely say that pick would have been one
of these seven or eight players
>> and um and we didn't feel like that
would help us as much as Jaylen W.
situation.
>> That was a tough one. Um here's why he's
so passionate. Um
I would say in in in in
my career as a coach, I've been lucky
enough to coach a lot of passionate
players that love the game. And I think
the
I'm always disappointed
um internally that that that didn't work
out. And because
um I love that player. I I love how he
competes. I love all the things he
brings and
you feel somewhat responsible when it
doesn't work out. So, um,
we knew it would take a little bit of
time with Alex and and Justin and, um,
you know, there's you're going to see
Ellis take some snaps inside. That's
something we've discussed relative to
our depth with the edge. Um, and then
we'll see where that goes during the
draft. But um
those aren't fun when you resign your
own players and I understand. But when
we look at the puzzle, you have to take
the red magnets that are UFAS and put
them off the depth chart and then begin
to address the must needs and wants.
>> Sean, the free agency process,
>> linebacker, tight end, running back.
Well, and it remember it starts if if if
you have a list that says must, needs,
and wants, you have to jump into the
draft first, jump back to free agency,
look at the draft again, and then begin
to look at where is the best way
to address this must
in the draft or in free agency. And and
look, we never get to live in a perfect
world, but you'd love to always be
drafting the best player. And sometimes
there's a lot of times that can happen.
So George and I, you know, we're all
sitting in there going through the
puzzle. And um yeah, I I think
there there were certain priorities.
Dobbins was a priority ahead of all
others. Now that'll anger people. He's
we know he's been injured. We
understand. and the injuries haven't
been soft tissue driven. But he's
someone that's one of those, you know,
those compound multipliers. Like he
brings 10 others along with him in a
positive light. Like our success last
year, he's got some fingerprints on
that. Dre has some, you know, all these
players that came in that have been in
winning programs.
Um,
>> you know, are are a big part of how you
win 14 games in in call it year three of
the program.
>> It's the decision to give him snaps
going forward.
>> What goes into that decision? Well,
skill set.
Um,
it's a position where where we're
wanting
like I had his I drafted his brother
and the same thing happened with Zack
Baughn only we couldn't get Zack Bone on
the field. Now, Philadelphia managed to
and
um
it was really looking at your assets and
and and we know he's smart, tough, he's
got all the and so sometimes that inside
backer position, you know, one of the
best in our league at San Francisco,
Fred Warner, you saw him play more, you
know, out in space, outside backer, and
then that. So sometimes you have to look
at the skill set and then project where
you think it can go and your depth on
the edge that allows you to do something
like that and and so we'll have a chance
to visit with him on that. I got a
question.
>> Inner circle first.
>> Well, let's get let's Yeah, I hear I I
saw the stories. All right. And I don't
I don't believe them.
And so it's not let's run it back. I
hate that term.
All right. It's not let's run it back.
Let's understand one thing. It's
anything but that. When you win 11 of 13
one-score games, like you saw the flip
in just one season between Kansas City,
it's how do you improve your team? And
the better you get, the harder it is to
improve your team. And so
you just weren't patient enough for us
to trade for Waddle. Your stories had
been written. I suggest you pursue.
>> Oh, come on. You had 10 other
suggestions, too.
>> And And listen, you can come get one of
these jobs.
>> Apply for one.
>> But did you feel Do you feel good where
you are now?
>> Well, I never feel good. I never feel
good. I think we have the draft coming
up. We're excited about that.
>> The point is though, there you have to
apply some patience
and and have a a good plan. and we
recognize where we're at. We we we
understand exactly where we're at with
Bose's contract, our team. And yet
the mistake twothirds of the teams make
is is trying to win the day, win the
draft day, win the hiring cycle day, and
win the free agency day. And we're
interested in winning.
And so
that's why our fan base is extremely
important to us, but
we're going to do what we think is best
for our team to be better when this
puzzle is finished at the end of call it
June and then
what do we look like at that point? But
I think honestly as as as a as a head
coach of a team and recognizing it was
great to see us compared to the year
before play very well in those one-sore
games. That's a byproduct of a little
confidence and it started I think in
Philadelphia. Like if you pinpointed a
couple key games, every one of you guys
would say, "Yeah, that was an important
moment, not just for Bo, but for a lot
of people." And then pretty soon, if
you're in that game the next time, you
feel like you can do it. And then, but
just go do the analytics
lopsided in your favor,
one one score games, which certainly 11
of 13 would be, and then track the next
season. And there's nothing that that
core. So
that's why I said to you, I never feel
good. I mean, it's you're always, you
understand the next challenge. We have a
tough schedule. We don't know when we're
playing these teams, but we're playing a
real good uh schedule, teams that have
been the postseason. So, but I do think
patience is important. My brother's 71
years old and day two of free agency,
the phone rings. Free agency frenzy
>> right here. you're the frenzy guy and if
it's frenzy that's not good but that
sells
>> one of the one of the things
how much not I mean obviously he's a
good player but how much does he impact
your other receivers and also
potentially just like your running game?
>> Well I I think this I think my
experience is when the locker room is
kind of where we have it if you can help
us come on in. if if you train and are
like-minded like us, come on in. now if
you can't and so I think whenever you're
able to bring in someone that's highly
competitive
um
his personality all of those things I
think um
I think the good teams welcome those
players because they know it's another
piece another opportunity to improve
your team
>> but on the field is he he's a bigger
impact than just
>> Yeah. So, if you guys said where does he
play,
man, he's he's played everywhere. I've
seen him outside as a tremendous route
runner inside.
Um,
the route tree is pretty expansive. I
I'd say I I just said it, the best thing
he that I think he does is he's
explosive, he's dynamic. A lot of times
the guys run fast, but I think he sinks
his hips in transition. So, I think
you'll see him play inside in the slot.
You'll see him play outside. We'll have
speed packages that'll feature, you
know, we'll have, you know, how we're
not just going to have, and I know
someone's getting ready to ask me, is he
receiver one or two? And so that we
don't have, we just play different
packages and try to try to give those
guys the things that they do. Well,
>> one of the things you get out of your
>> Well,
that was humbling. I I think this
you remember the Home Alone series and
McCauley Caulkin was inside. Well,
McCaulay Caulkin was the international
team and I felt like coach Harbaugh and
I were the two guys outside getting hit
in the head with the iron and tripping
over the garden hose. Um, it's it's an
entirely different game. I I don't think
and but I listen it was it was kind of
cool to be around those guys like that
was a big deal and I I think when this
first was announced there was this
feeling there would be 10 NFL players on
that roster and I'll be surprised if
there's one. I just think I think we
have plenty of players that can
acclimate, but it's going to take a
month or two. And then if you're one of
those players, do you have that month or
two?
And if you're training for that, you're
not training, you know, and so I just
think it's in it's in a good spot. it it
I thought it was great for our
international team and more importantly
great for the women's side of it because
there's an avenue where they can play
football and and so talking with one of
the women players on the international
team for the US they're recruiting or
looking at like where does the flag team
recruit female players and they're
looking at NC2A basketball and they're
finding point guards
that maybe aren't tall enough to to play
further. um and she was a college guard
and everything is start stop quick. Um
but needless to say and look it'd be
easy if we said we didn't take it
seriously. I mean spent some time on
that and and and
um yeah it was kind of humbling.
>> Sean, one of the things you highlighted
after the year, you know, in terms of
the margin per run game and the
consistency it, you know, right now
right now all the runners who grew are
the same.
>> Understand that. How do you take
>> Well, so right now I'm going to answer
the question, but look, that could be a
position that gets addressed if if the
opportunity presents itself. Look, we
love the way R.J. played. Um, and and
we ran it more consistently earlier in
the year than we did later in the year.
Um, I don't like how we rushed it in the
postseason. Um, it's it's it's one way
to take pressure off your quarterback
and and I think that's that'll be a
focus.
coaching programs pretty well defined
for years.
>> Yeah.
>> April running
with Davis now calling. Does that
change? What's your schedule look like?
>> Doesn't change anything. Um,
>> it doesn't change any of that. Um, look,
typically we come in in April. The first
four weeks, I know what the league's
phases are. We we kind of tweak it. Um,
I always want the first month to be in
the weight room. nothing to do with
football. So, this year we went three
weeks further into the season. Our
players won't be in our building until
May, the first Monday in May. I think
it's third or fourth. Um, and then all
of May will just be weightlifting.
You'll see us on the field in June. Um,
we'll have two weeks of OTAAS and a week
of mini camp, but I don't want them to
feel like they were just here. So, I've
done that before. Um, I think it's
important and I think the players
appreciate it because they were just
here.
>> Talk about uh your staff.
>> We've got a handful of guys um and
that's part of the deal. Robert
obviously locally coming right from
Colorado. Um, a lot of background with
him, Vance certainly and and a number of
us um on the staff knew if we didn't
know him, we knew others that work with
him. Um,
and then, uh, Ronald Curry, of course,
um, who played at North Carolina as a
two sport athlete. It's pretty amazing.
He was good. He
>> He was He was He was great at
basketball. He was He was a lottery or
not a lot, what is it? A He was one of
these guys that
>> slam dunk champion.
So,
I' I've had Ronald. He's he's a
fantastic coach. He became available
um after and and right away we had a
chance to bring him in. You guys will
love him. Um and then there there are a
handful of other coaches, you know, that
are that are filling in spots. Um either
guys have been promoted or guys have had
opportunities elsewhere. So that's part
of the deal.
Going back to the one score you talked
about and like leading that many
gamewinning drives and Caleb Williams
from Chicago had a similar situation. Is
there
>> It wasn't that similar though. It's a
little different.
>> But is there a carryover?
>> Bose was better.
>> Well, I think I think he actually had
more in the regular season. One more.
So, you're right about
>> less in the postseason, but keep going.
>> The carryover effect to the next year.
Is there anything you expect with
quarterbacks or is that just like
>> I I think this and and and I was being
funny. I think for both of those players
You guys have heard me say this,
confidence can only be born out of
demonstrated ability. And so I would ask
everyone here, if I said to you, Jaylen
and Bo, are they more confident this
year? Absolutely. Um, now
there's nothing that says that's
promised the next year. And so, and Ben
knows this, you know, you you you turn
the board upside down, you place it, and
you collect your pieces, whatever the
game is, and you start yet, you have to
start back at zero. But when you start
back there, you've got a a little bit of
a bank vault that is that is filled with
these positive experiences. And if you
believe it can happen once
and then and so you're a different
player at the start of this season than
you were at the start of the other
season. But the one-core score games I I
think it just provides you
in in the college game there far fewer
of those games. And so it provides you
with this is more the norm. We might be
down six, up six, up three, tied at
half. Like you get used to living in
that world. I I think that's a big
thing, especially for the quarterback.
>> Coach, I got a question.
>> Competition between steady back.
>> We see competition. No. No, no, there's
no no there's and it wasn't different
last year. It's there's nothing that's
etched in stone with like it there just
isn't. And so and that's a good thing.
>> Go ahead.
>> For for Bo, when you evaluate these
first two years, you know, I know growth
theater, etc., but what is a year three,
you know, continued development look
like? I I think look his job and we we
say this all the time it's is get your
lead your team into the end zone lead
your team to wins and so I think man we
see him every day at the facility um
you know he's doing he's ahead of
schedule with his rehab he likes being
around football and uh
you know
that
draft and the significance of getting
trying to get that right is like holy
cow. Um,
it's so important and and and look,
we'll be able to grade that whole class,
you know,
I always say three years out, well, we
we could begin to apply that and then
certainly 10 years out, you really know,
but um yeah, I think
I think the tweaks, the changes, the
additions um and then understanding
the the challenges es ahead.
>> What do you think Davis being in that
thing?
>> Well, I think it changes changes for
Davis and Bo a little like Bo's in there
with Logan Kilgore now,
>> you know, and
Logan will be his warm fuzzy
and now Davis and myself will be like,
"Hey, what do you you know?" Um
I look, I think they have a great
relationship. I think
there's a um real cohesive there's a
cohesiveness co cohesiveness in general
with our sides of the ball and you know
and so
I'll still be working in every of the
offensive meetings with um and so I I
just think that um
yeah it's it's I'm glad we have Davis
coming back and
and I think that uh yeah that experience
will will only help us.
>> Go ahead.
>> You talked a lot about. Can you tell us
why you have confidence
that
>> he's played quarterback um he was in our
training camp in New Orleans. I'm kind
of giving you his background, but I
think he's clearly one of those guys
that has demonstrated um that maturity
that you look for for a coach that goes
into um an advanced position. And it
starts with can you promote from within
and I think it's something that's welld
deserved. I mean he's earned it.
>> Yeah.
>> I look the carryover I told you at the
combine I'll say it again. I was
surprised. Um and yet there's a part of
me that's not surprised. Um when I when
I say a handful can't get out of their
own way. I meant that. And um so there's
great parody in our league, but there's
great consistency with some teams in our
league as well.
>> Sean,
>> well, the first thing
you know exactly what you're getting in
the player and so look, if we want to
run the ball well, he's one of the
better blocking tight ends. He's he's
really good in pass protection. Um we
evaluate every ounce of the tape. So,
like be lerary of someone that grabs
three clips and we know exactly what
Adam is and and
that was just going to take time to see
where the market valued him. And so I'm
glad he's back and and and I don't take
him for granted because we knew look
when you have Declan who's left and you
have these other coaches Pete and Jim
the other challenge with that is they
have a little bit more exposure to your
free agents relative to and so that was
a little bit of a concern.
>> We're going clockwise right now if you
guys haven't noticed.
Do you have that in your bag?
>> I don't have anything warm and fuzzy in
my golf bag except except for the towel.
>> As you go through, obviously last year
in the draft there was some tight ends
that were like this class seems like
it's a little deeper. What do you make
of the tight end?
>> All right. So, in fairness to the
question, we did our front board
meetings prior to the combine, which is
an overview.
Today's Tuesday. tomorrow morning at
7:30 we we enter that team meeting room
and we're in there for the next 26 days.
Um certainly at the combine like I think
there's some really good prospects
but I'm anxious to see who they are cuz
right now I just know the names like I
mean I honestly I just know them like
you do. Hopefully we can get to know
them and and and possibly have a target
in there.
All right. What's the first Monday in
May?
>> May 4.
>> So May, all of May will be weights in
running and then June will be OTAA week
one, OTAA week two, mini camp week
three.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Now that you had two months a
championship, how do you feel about
anything?
>> As bad as Yeah.
Well, yes. There's a ton of things. All
right. Thank you guys.